Guide to the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University, photographs
1961-1963
RU 106
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.71
(10 boxes)
The collection consists of photographs documenting the construction of Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library at Yale. Included are pre-construction views, construction progress views, and completed interior and exterior views. Also included are photographs of the opening ceremonies and reception.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of photographs documenting the construction of Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library at Yale. Included are pre-construction views, construction progress views, and completed interior and exterior views. Also included are photographs of the opening ceremonies and reception.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Academic libraries -- Design and construction; College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University. Library
- Photographs, Series I
  - Construction (general)
    - Model (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1961: Pre-construction site views (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1961: site excavation (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
    - 1961: construction views (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1961 -1963: construction views (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - 1962: construction views (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1962 -1963: construction views (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Construction views (contact sheets) (Box 1, Folder 10 - 13)
  - Construction progress photographs
    - 1961 May -Aug (Box 1, Folder 14 - 18)
    - 1961 Sep -1962 Aug (Box 2, Folder 19 - 38)
    - 1962 Sept -1963 Apr (Box 3, Folder 39 - 52)
    - 1963 Apr -- 1963 Sept (Box 4, Folder 53 - 64)
    - Construction, undated (Box 5, Folder 65 - 78)
    - Construction, miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Ice damage, leaks, etc. (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Opening Ceremonies, 1963
    - Speakers (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Reception (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Dinner in University Dining Hall (Commons) (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Exterior, undated (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Interior
    - 1963 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - n.d. (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Display cases, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Display cases, undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Book stacks, collection, undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Oversize
    - Interior (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Under construction (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Slides and transparencies
    - Slides (Box 8)
    - Transparencies (Box 9)
- Additional Material, 1961; Accession 2015-A-050
  - Authorization, purpose and procedure and investigation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of buildings, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Woodbridge Hall, 1961 April-May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - University Dining Hall, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Woolsey Hall, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Book and Snake, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scroll and Key, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Utilities tunnel - South tunnel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sprague Memorial Hall, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - W.L. Harkness Hall, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Berkeley College, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sterling Memorial Library, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sterling Law Building, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General summary, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)